FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER · MECHATRONICS ENGINEER · TECH ENTHUSIAST

N71-38 John F. Kennedy, Pablo Picasso, Quito, 170301, Ecuador

🛘 (+593) 98 747 3691 GMT-5 | 💌 info@guidosantillan.com | 🗥 www.guidosantillan.com | ☐ quidosantillan01 | ☐ quido92 | ☑ Guido_Santillan

Date of Birth: 28.12.1992 Nationality: Ecuadorian Marital Status: Single



Summary _____

Junior Web Developer experienced in all stages of the software development cycle. Good understanding of webrelated technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git, REST. Hands-on experience developing web applications using React, Node, Express, and PostgreSQL. A fast learner and hard-working individual who adapts quickly to assess an organization's needs. Actively looking forward to expanding my knowledge, improve my skills and obtain relevant experience in the IT industry in order to help create world-changing solutions.

Projects_

Syder Ideas Quito, Ecuador INDEPENDENT DEVELOPER January 2019

- Syder Ideas is a web application which you can store your side-project ideas in an intuitive and systems-based way.
- Front-end developed in React. Back-end uses NodeJS and Express. It is hosted on Heroku.
- Stores all data in a PostgreSQL database.
- Designed authentication and authorization scheme with Auth-0 JWTs and Passport.
- Ongoing open source project hosted on GitHub.

Experience _____

Project Manager Quito, Ecuador Oct 2016 - present

ECUAFRANQUICIAS

• Automation of multiple internal processes using office automation tools and Excel to reduce in half the time needed to deliver the product to our clients while simultaneously detecting errors in the development stage and giving employees more autonomy to develop their daily tasks.

- While the processes automation improved a lot of things, it was not enough to maximize the performance of the employees, a system was needed. This system will use modern web technologies to gather, store, and manage information in an accessible way for our employees via the internet.
- Documentation of the operative and administrative processes of our clients.
- Implementation of email marketing campaigns using MailChimp to approximately 3000+ subscribers.
- An SEO strategy was put in place to improve local search results, it helped us reach the first positions in Google. This strategy consisted of a webpage redesign, webpage optimization, keyword research and analysis, content creation, webpage analytics.

Web Developer Ouito. Ecuador INDEPENDENT WORK June 2017 - present

- Performed website design and development for clients in diverse fields such as consulting, non-profit organizations, and law firms using various CMS.
- Websites were designed with a focus on achieving maximum performance, faster loading times, mobile-friendly and optimized for SEO purposes.

Research and Teaching Assistant of Computer-aided Design, Manufacture and Engineering subject (CAD, CAM, CAE)

Quito, Ecuador

DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY AND MECHANIC SCIENCES - ESPE

Nov. 2015 - Feb. 2016

- Modeling, analysis, and manufacture of a vehicle-based RIN.
- Elaboration of processes sheets, strain simulation and post-processing of the manufacturing operations.

GUIDO SANTILLÁN · CURRICULUM VITAE

Undergraduate Researcher, Manufacturing Processes Lab.

ARMY FORCES UNIVERSITY - ESPE

Quito, Ecuador. Jan. 2015 - Mar. 2015

• Design and development of mobile robots using 3D printing and laser cutting techniques.

Education_

International Exchange Student

Brandenburg an der Havel, Germany

March - Sept. 2016

TECHNISCHE HOCHSCHULE BRANDENBURG

• Development of thesis project "Implementation of HIL/SIL simulation techniques for real-time tests of vehicle models using the DSPACE platform"

- GPA: A-
- System modelling | Vehicle dynamics | Embedded systems

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), in Mechatronics Engineering

Quito, Ecuador

Apr. 2011 - Feb. 2016

ARMY FORCES UNIVERSITY - ESPE

• GPA: 17.43/20

• Industrial Robotics | Mechatronic Automation | CAD/CAM/CAE

Skills____

LANGUAGES:

Spanish Native

English Fluent - Sufficiency in English Certificate completed at ESPE

German Basic - A1 completed at Technische Hochschule Brandenburg - Germany

PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE:

Web development HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bulma, Javascript, GIT, Webpack, eslint, prettier, Postman

Frontend React, Redux, React-Router, GatsbyJS

BackendNodeJS, ExpressTestingJest, EnzymeDatabasesPostgreSQLHostingNetlify, Heroku

CMS Wordpress

Machine Learning Pytorch, Jupyter

Others Python, Pandas, Arduino, Processing, MEX

Basic experience C, C++, Java

OTHER:

Media Adobe Indesign, Adobe Illustrator, Sony Vegas

Digital Marketing Search Engine Optimization, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Email Marketing

CAD/CAM/CAE SolidWorks, AutoCAD 2D/3D, Siemens NX

Mathematical Analysis Matlab/Simulink, LabVIEW

Electronic Design Proteus, Multisim

Honors & Awards

2016	Honorable Mention, Awarded by the Army Forces University's principal	Quito, Ecuador
2016	Winner, EXPOINDUSTRIAL 2016 Mechatronics Competition – FESTO CHALLENGE	Quito, Ecuador
2016	High Performance Scholarship , Awarded by the <i>Army Forces University</i> to develop	Quito, Ecuador
	research projects in Germany	